#### AVATAR SINGH PATLE

Email: Patleavatar@gmail.com | +919009120469

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/avatar-patle-devops-cloud905144226

GitHub: Avatar1992 (Avatar Patle) · GitHub

Portfolio: avatar1992.github.io (portfolio website)

### **Summary**

Over 5.2-year experience as DevOps and Cloud Engineer, Design, implement, and maintain Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment pipelines and Automate build, test, and deployment processes. Use tools like Terraform, CloudFormation, or Ansible to provision and manage infrastructure. Set up monitoring tools Prometheus, Grafana. Automate repetitive tasks using shell scripts, Python, or other scripting languages. Architect and manage cloud environments with AWS. Implement cloud security best practices with IAM and Deploy applications and services in cloud environments.

#### **Skills and Tools**

**Linux:** Shell Scripting, Package & Service Management **CI/CD**: Jenkins, GitHub Actions and Argo CD + Jenkins

IaC: Terraform, Ansible

**Containers**: Docker, Kubernetes

**Cloud Platforms**: AWS

Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana

Version Control: Git

### Experience

Reliance Property Project Limited | PUNE

### **DevOps Cloud Support Engineer** - Sep 2020 to till date

- Ensure builds and deployments are running smoothly.
- Fix broken pipelines or failed deployments.
- Optimize pipeline performance and reduce build times.
- Manage container-based deployments with ECS, EKS, and Fargate.
- Automate infrastructure with CloudFormation or Terraform.
- Manage AWS services: EC2, S3, RDS, IAM, VPC, etc.

## Accord synergy ltd | PUNE

## RNO (Airtel -Nokia Project) July 2019 to Sep 2020

- Improved network efficiency by optimizing latency and bandwidth.
- Configured and maintained routers and switches with VLANs and routing protocols (OSPF, BGP).

#### Secure link PVT ltd | PUNE

# Project Coordinator (BSNL, Airtel, Vodafone -Nokia Project)

Feb 2017 to July 2019

- organizes and manages the various parts of a project to ensure its success.
- Coordinates, and has direct responsibility for, a project or specific set of tasks related to a function or program or department/business unit
- Managing DPR & MDB and P&L

### Syncroute Infranet Pvt Ltd | MH

## DT Eng. (Airtel, Vodafone -Nokia Project and Jio – Samsung project)

Mar 2016 to Feb 2017

- Worst KPIs cells improvement analysis.
- Managing customer complain for low throughput.

### Ahead industry Pvt Ltd | MP CG, GU, RJ and MH

### DT Eng. (Airtel, Vodafone -Nokia & Ericson Project and Jio – Samsung project)

Mar 2015 to Feb 2016

- Worst KPIs cells improvement analysis.
- Managing customer complain for low throughput.

Tech C.S.R

Mphasis | Indore

Mar 2014 to Feb 2015

# Education

RGPV | Bhopal B.E in Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering 2013 MP Borad | 12<sup>th</sup> 2009 MP Borad | 10<sup>th</sup> 2007

# Personal details

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Married

Date of Birth: 05/01/1992

Languages Known: English, Hindi.

Permanent Address: Savangi, Katangi Dist.Balaghat -481445